I get the question all the time what
yoga do I do and I want to talk about
that really briefly so I do I'm an old
guy and I believe in
modifying
in W to get something that's healthy for
you so I do
Ashtanga uh you can go to tummy. comom I
don't have a uh I don't have a an ex all
my my sequence on here yet but if you go
to tm.com t.com
um you can kind of make your own
sequence up but but in I started out
doing a shanga so the best place to
learn about asanga is here uh asanga
yoga. info mostly this is in German
unfortunately um I mostly agree with
this
sequence um that's here and you can go
download
it uh if I can find it here shanga
yoga and traditional practice practice
series inspiration for yoga
uh cheat sheets or you can get the PDFs
for this um I really like Ron Steiner
because he is a physical therapist as
well as an aaga Yogi and so he you know
he's he's done all of it so I'm just
going to summarize really quick so I
do because I TR I want to finish in an
hour and I'm and I'm going to tell you
some things and there's going to be some
yoga people that are going to come
unglued okay so let me tell you that you
have permission to make yoga into what
your body needs and and there are a lot
of people that disagree with that
particularly in the asanga tradition and
they they love to tell people what to do
they get really dogmatic about it a lot
like religion um I think that's silly so
if you want to see a great video about
that about why it's silly to get all
crazy about a tradition go to YouTube
and search for a woman named Maddie
isra this
Maddie is r
and uh see if we can find her that is
not her Maddie AA
asanga I don't know if
e
Ezra
Yoga isra
Yoga H and you go listen to her talk
this is it this is a video M isanga yoga
she's talking about it she's my favorite
ashtangi uh she's not with us anymore
but she talks really a lot about about
which one to do and how you know don't
get so caught up in all that so but so
to summarize what I do I do sun a sun a
to build heat in the body but I don't I
don't do sun a more than I need because
I just need to build up the heat and get
my body warm so I can do the rest of
yoga that's the purpose of sun a for me
um my wife does sometimes she'll do 25
or 50 Sun a is kind of a workout and
that's fine if you can't do anything but
just Sun a and then do the finishing
sequence and jump to the to the end
um you've done yoga for the day right
and um a lot of people will struggle
with sun a especially if you're larger
which I was I lost a lot of weight uh I
did a lot of cycling to lose weight I
started to do yoga and then I gave it up
because I was I wanted to do you know
the yoga that I had been doing every day
and I couldn't because I was too heavy
and I mean it was like destroying my my
my wrists and a bunch of things because
I again I was just really really heavy
so doing just Sun a is to lower your
weight or to to get you know the benefit
from that that might be enough um you
know but but put together your own
sequence uh the only thing you really
need to know is make sure you have a
counter pose for every single pose you
do so like if you do a fold over make
sure you counter with something that
folds your back um and and you know
inter intermix them if another thing you
can do is you can
intermix poses that make you breathe
really heavy with poses that are
relaxing and um that's like some of the
the main guidance there uh other than
that because I've been influenced by the
asaga tradition uh I've been doing these
poses for years since
2010 uh I've been doing these poses um
and you know it comes and goes my
flexibility comes and goes over time
when I don't do it U but I really like
the nature of asanga because it's it's
very do this thing and then do this
thing and don't focus on the form don't
hurt yourself but but work more on
focusing your mind and doing it kind of
like ta Chi but that makes you breathe
heavier right because it's more it's
better workout that's my take on it
that's why I like it it is a workout it
does it does really Tire me uh so I'm so
much so I had to give up cycling at the
end of the day because it's just too
after after 60 minutes for me I'm 57 and
after 60 Minutes of doing aanga yoga
with the jump throughs which are
basically a push-up um then a burpee
pushup then I you know I don't have
anything left so
um at least for now I've had to give up
cycling at the end of the day maybe you
know maybe my fitness will continue to
improve and I can eventually do some
cycling at the end day this this these
this I've done cycling on the on the
weekend I scheduled it for the weekend
beginning of November beginning of
November I'll start doing outdoor
cycling again um but for now I need to
finish moving and I need that energy so
so the fundamental position they have
sunay uh and I'm not going to
demonstrate I'm just talking about it if
you actually want to see me doing yoga
the only way to do that is to come on
Twitch because I play music that's
copyrighted in DJ mode which is totally
valid and legal and um so it you know
those the videos go away so you'd have
to come join me on Twitch for that in
the morning at 9:00 a.m. um but if you
want to do that then you can come see me
do these sequences and maybe kind of
learn a little bit about them while
you're watching I'm not going to act out
every every single one of those poses um
then I do the fundamental positions uh
which
are uh see if I can zoom in on this a
little bit
um let's go up to 100% at least
110% um I wish it would go
bigger I wish it would go way
bigger oh if I did this what does this
do I'm going probably have to just
download it so anyway you do you pulled
over so the the S stand for sa C he
that's because you're standing up up
straight this tells you just just just
break this down for you so this these
are all the Sanskrit names uh one of the
reasons I showed you this other site is
because it does have the English and the
Sanskrit names so you can decide if you
want to do that or not I don't actually
don't know the the uh English names for
some of them this
isas so this one this one is you know
stretch your back out and hamstrings
don't overdo it obviously it tells you
where to look that's what the nose is
about tells you your inhale exhale
almost every one of these poses ends
with five breaths uh regular breasts not
not um not uh um a lot people confuse
that a lot of people do U breathing they
think that's what yoga is it's not yoga
does yoga breathing is a part of Prana
prara sorry that is you know breathing
exercises which are part of yoga but the
but the the implication that that that
that breathing is what's happening in in
Aang is totally wrong people say that
all the time
uh is deep Long breaths and that kind of
sound like Darth Vader while you're
doing them and even though the breathing
between these poses is deep and you know
sometimes it's gut roll and everything
you it's usually faster than a c us
breathing and if you if you go into this
thinking I'm going to do all these
really hard work and I'm not I've got to
breathe like I ate really long slow
breasts that's wrong because you you
need to breathe more frequently than
that by the way if you do start needing
to breathe like more than the breathing
CP in aanga um it usually means you're
pushing too hard and you need to take a
break and that's actually a good thing
physically for you too because that'll
put you back in zone two as opposed to
pushing in you know up into Tempo and
and other you know higher rates uh for
working out now you can do and I have
done you can do aanga in kind of fast
mode and make it sort of this you know
really intense workout as long as you
don't you know overly stretch or break
anything and I've done that too and
there's nothing wrong with that
so sometimes I just feel like getting a
really good workout so I will push the
pace on it uh I'll still breathe but
I'll just make the breathing much faster
sometimes I feel like I when I'm really
hurting sometimes I'll feel like holding
a pose for 20 seconds instead of f five
breaths which is is the minimum you need
to actually have a stretch effect
effectively take hold on in your muscles
that's we had to learn that for training
so asanga has you only doing the poses
for five breaths and that alone is not
going to it will over time make small
changes to your body but if you like
want to open your hamstrings or you're
be able to do you know full Lotus or
something you that's not going to be
enough you're you're going to have to
have some of those poses be extended for
a certain amount of time I'm going to
show you one thing that I do way more
than about 2 minutes every time I do
this because of in my back I roll out my
back because I'm a coder and a cyclist
and we'll talk about that so this is
there's a triangle pose um you can
modify all these uh my favorite book to
get on this is David Swinson's book uh
this is if I was going to recommend you
buy
anything uh this is the one I would
recommend you get um ARA yoga.net he
does some videos for
free uh the book I have the tattered
book I have on the ground over here here
where is it right there that is my
asanga yoga manual and the reason I
think it's the most important book for
any beginner to get is because it
actually has all the modifications in it
and you can flip the pages and it tells
you in excruciating detail what to do um
if you're going to go with the ISA
tradition I recommend that because that
that will go into actually what you do
for every pose uh there's other couple
books out there but that's the one that
that I like the most um and then when we
go back to where did it go
so uh if we go back to this where was I
come on Rob good old Maddie so so you
know you you do the bending over um this
is the dep down now a lot of these I I
modify them all because I can't this
this particular sequence right here
where you're touching the ground uh if
you don't have the flexibility to touch
the ground it's a totally different
exercise because it actually activates
your hand strengths because it uses them
and it's a different exercise completely
hey balum so just so you know um some of
the modifications are going to work your
body out in different ways or actually
some of them will actually tighten the
muscles you're working to stretch or to
to flex it to open up and if you do this
particular pose uh and you can't touch
the ground you are doing a totally
different thing but I'm okay with that
so um so here it goes there's this 3
three right there uh and then this is a
venas so basically your Su C he you bend
over you look up you jump back or put
your foot back and then you you hold
your toes under you roll up you go down
you go you do another burp you can hold
it right there and you know flexible uh
you know like straighten the back as
much as you can go up and then go back
down and then and then you can jump
through uh your feet so that's how you
go all the way up right uh if you want
to go back up the standing but you can
also do this sequence and you go to
right here and then you uh you either
jump your feet through your arms back to
sitting or sta pose and then you start
the next one so that's that's what they
call a basa which means flow uh between
the different poses so again this video
is designed to be a summary you can stop
it and and anytime you want uh people
ask questions about why I do this type
of yoga so the other main sequence to
know is the finishing sequence this is
at the very end and um and then there's
there's kind of a sandwich in the middle
and that's primary and we'll talk about
that uh opens the heart so far it does
um so uh doing doing a binasa like that
as you can tell tell when you're doing
up dog it it does it opens up your heart
it flexes you know it opens your back
and your Muses it's also an inversion so
it gets blood flow to your brain you
know and kind of so so just doing that's
what I said just doing sunas that the
Vasa right there is a sun a
right it's a sun a and you basically do
a sun a between all the poses whether
you land in standing or sitting same
thing right it's a sun a which is why if
you're just doing Sun you get a good
workout and it'd be really great um so
this here is this is the finishing
sequence and I need to talk about this
um first of all uh Ron Steiner has added
more to the finishing sequence than than
is actually in the finishing sequence
he's made some adaptations to a strong
tends people tend to do that um the
finishing sequence actually
starts uh with uh a back band and he
doesn't have back band in his um and you
know he's got all of this other stuff
here so again this is just a video
commenting on what I've done in my yoga
uh I do this I I do I I've just recently
I've
eliminated uh these poses because
they're horrible horrible horrible on my
neck and uh I can't risk it I have a
really bad neck my neck has gotten
messed up over because of years of of of
Athletics and and different things and
and computer work and all kinds of
reasons I have a a very sharp uh spine
when it hits it hits my shoulder and a
big part of yoga is understanding your
body and then adapting yoga for your
body uh this is where having an actual
certified yoga person or um you know a
physical therapist or something get
involved with what you're going to do is
to help you adjust your body you really
need to be be careful particular with
back things um and you know people get
injured in yoga all the time because
they think they're supposed to do the
exact pose so my I have a very sharp
inward curve on my you everybody's got
the curve in their neck like this but
mine is really sharp and and I'm
actually looking to do some head
traction um uh in order to to work on
that I I can't recommend it to anybody I
would make sure you get you don't I
don't know about a chiropractor but you
know licensed physical therapist if
you're going to start to do that kind of
thing um but the yoga I've been doing
has been making me really aware of that
part and when you get up my age you know
you got to be aware of all that stuff so
um head traction is they have a thing
that you can put on your head and you
you basically just you know put your
head in a vice or in in a a strap and
then you let the weight of your body
pull down on your neck and straighten
your neck and open up the columns
between your uh uh between your neck to
kind of straighten your neck out uh
obviously super dangerous you don't want
everybody to do it I'm not recommending
you do it but I'm telling you mostly
here the reason I don't do these poses
anymore uh some of you have been
watching me do yoga you've seen me do
them uh everything that is covered by
these poses I believe is covered
elsewhere better uh and I and gar would
agree right so um this is an inversion
which you can do with handstand which I
do which is this is very safe this is
actually one of the most safest
inversions you can ever do uh if you
learn how to do it we'll talk about that
in a second so this all of this stuff is
designed I guess to open up your you see
how sharply U the turn is on the head
though that's the real dangerous part
and yes it's an inversion and yes it it
squishes your organs and gets it all set
up uh and it's got you know it's got a
lotus in there and I can actually do
Lotus here better when I'm inverted than
I can when I'm sitting down but uh as
far as I'm concerned the only purpose
for this physically is to get the
inversion all the reasons for getting an
inversion and to open up your hamstrings
um and both of those things can be done
both of those things can easily be done
more safely with other poses in fact
these any of these poses like this are
not included in any yoga tradition
whatsoever uh outside of a stronga so I
don't I don't do them I've eliminated
them and that saved me a lot of time
actually um however I do make sure to do
this so this is a shasana this is called
shoulder stand and I want to be really
careful with this I've the reason I'm
making this video is because people
watch me and they see me do a headstand
and they call it a handstand or
headstand it's not the head is only
barely touching the mat on this pose
there is another variation on this uh in
and it's another version of yoga where
they actually do headstands there's
people who literally stand only on their
head in yoga super dangerous super
stupid I would never do it I can't
recommend it to anybody um and inversion
is super important for your body you
need to get inverted you need to get
that blood flowing in the other
direction it's actually really makes you
really high afterwards but they have you
like laying in a Crouch position after
this for you know 5 10 15 breaths or
something and then and then you're ready
to you know to come up for air uh you
know if if you do inversion and by the
way downward dogs are also inversions
that are not as intense so you don't end
up with an aneurysm if you're going to
get an aneurysm it's going to happen
while you're doing an inversion like
this so don't don't be stupid don't
overdo it listen to your body but if you
can learn how to do a proper shoulder
stand I think it's one of the best poses
you can do um because it it does it
literally invert you your your body is
absolutely straight all of the uh
balancing all of the muscular uh
activation for the balancing is
happening in your upper shoulder girdle
there is no head balancing happening at
all there occasionally I mean your head
is touching the ground uh yeah you could
and but occasionally your head will
touch the ground when you're doing it
but if it does touch the ground it
should only be for a slight second while
you re regain your balance across your
shoulder across your hands and your
hands are you know your hand your here
the pressure points in the mat are right
here and cross your shoulders right here
I mean cross your um across your
forearms right they call it forearm
stand but I just I want to be really
that's one of the ones the poses I
really want to talk about because people
see me doing that all the time and I'm
so terrified that someone's just going
to try it and not know what they're
doing and really hurt themselves um uh
you know that's one of the reasons I
almost considered not streaming yoga um
and then and then you you come down uh I
do spread leg uh here you can also do
this this is really really really good
on your back uh it's really it's a lot
of strain on your your back however this
is like a lot of straight on your lower
back and so if you if you don't want to
risk it don't do it if your lower back's
not strong enough yet don't do it um and
then you do this you can you can come
into I I actually have put some poses in
here um in between this pose and this
pose where he's doing B this is bound
Lotus I I do love these final poses
right here so I've eliminated sh I've
eliminated shasa which is you lay down
for 20 minutes I don't do it anymore I
don't I I see the value of it but I
don't do it I would rather the whole
point of a is to get ready for
meditation so I actually rather that's
the last pose by the way shasana uh
rather than do shasana I actually sit uh
I'll do some PR prara I'll do some
breathing I'll do some Nali which is a
special type of breathing uh that helps
shrink your inner organs and um and then
I'll do uh uh another I forget the name
of it but it's uh it's not I don't have
the flexibility to do have typical Lotus
eventually I would I would say in if
full Lotus but right now I just sit with
my sit very grounded and I do meditation
I do meditation I do tana and darana
which are focused meditations I'll do
I'll I'll listen to music and just focus
on the lyrics I'll I'll do is it the
what's the candle gazing called I'll
just stare at a light for five or 10
minutes rather than just lay down for 20
minutes um there's nothing wrong with
laying down some of the best thing
sometimes I fall asleep and it's a nice
20-minute nap if you want to do that but
I don't I I'll usually do meditation
right here instead um because I don't
have that much time if I ever an AA
practi all the stuff I've cut out of it
it would still take me almost 90 minutes
to do the whole thing and so I don't do
that but the other thing about the
finishing sequence that I have done uh
is to build and this comes uh from a
book about uh uh building uh building
your body to be able to do
uh B bakasana which is uh bound half po
Lotus and most Americans most westerners
are not able to do full lus so what I've
done here is I've injected in between
here here I do I I do a side stretch
because there's almost no side stretches
in yoga particularly in asanga there's
nothing that works the side body there's
nothing that stretches a side body there
is in in batist yoga but there's not in
in asanga um and other than you know the
the reaching out stuff from the early uh
sequence but so I usually will do that
and that's that's what I do to pull out
of it then I'll I'll do hero pose which
they don't show here I don't know why
they're not showing hero here that's
actually a part of the pose where you
stand up and you're got your hands there
and you just let that stretch out the
front of your
leg uh Americans have sit we've been
we've been westerners have been sitting
in chairs since since they were kids if
they had been sitting on the ground
since they were kids they'd easily be be
able to do it so the main reason between
uh the Eastern uh civilizations and
cultures and the Western cultures uh
most westerners there's no way they'll
ever be able to do full Lotus most
easterners can do full Lotus and could
since they were 8 years old because you
we've been sitting like I am the way
that I'm sitting our our hamstrings and
our hips and everything are are being
contracted on purpose the way we sit um
if if you want to actually open your
body up I see people in gamer chairs all
the time and it just makes me winse in
pain I'm like how can you sit in that um
I suggest if you get a chair like mine I
like mine this is a very cheap chair if
you get a chair like mine mine is is is
you know it's got ventilation which is
really important if you spend 12 hours
in a chair you know I did a 12 hour
stream the other day and the second
thing is is it's comfortable enough that
I can actually sit in half Lotus on here
and that
this is so much better for your body
than sitting in a chair the regular way
uh in fact I seriously consider in this
new office of mind putting all of this
stuff on the ground and actually
streaming from the ground streaming in
in h you know in Lotus the whole time uh
when I first started my Tech Career uh
when I well after the divorce I when I
was making my my house up I I took my
laptop around with me everywhere and I
would I would do different yoga poses
all over and since I started streaming I
was super happy this from the laptop
because I technically I could take my
laptop and I could sit in in Cobra pose
which is you know on your tummy with you
know reverse arching your back instead
of hunching over your keyboard and you
know you could vary I've even done legs
up the wall which is you know stand next
to sit next to the wall so be very
conscious of your of your ergonomics but
the most important thing is is
developing the back strength and the
back flexibility and we're going to talk
about this later a little bit that you
you you've got to counter the hunching
if you don't counter the hunching you
will end you've seen old people with
hunches by the time they hit 60 right
you've seen what happens and uh they
they lose they lose height they get
these big hunchbacks on going on and the
only way to combat that is to learn how
to sit properly just straight up
maintain your back strength and your
your butt strength build a booty my
friend used to say and and you know and
to sit like with your with your you know
your your hips and everything grounded
and that way that'll straighten your
back up a little bit and you'll you'll
you'll be now it's hard to do this
actually it's hard you can't it's not
relaxing to sit like I mean it it is but
but it it's firing different muscles
it's firing core muscles down here all
the time you know people that sit on
Bouncy bells and stuff that's that's
well and good but you're still sitting
in a seated pose um you know what I'm
saying you're you're still sitting in a
seated pose and the problem with a
seated pose is it's it's totally locking
your hamstrings up completely
so um anyway so so what I've in inserted
into here is specific uh I the book
about you know full Lotus that I read it
it shows you all the poses to prepare to
be able to sit this way uh in a way
that's you know healthy and uh and those
poses are pigeon and you'll see me do
that it's way you're doing downward dog
and then you kick your leg up and you
run it through and then you kind of like
you arch up and then you like lay down
on sort of your leg while it's there and
you can feel the stretch across the back
of your ass and and that and then I do
and then I do the after I do that I do
uh uh Timber log pose which is where you
have your legs out in front of you and
you kind of put one foot over the knee
here I'll show you so Timber log is like
this you'd have
like here I'll just do one
Timber legs this so you have one leg
like
this right one leg like this and then
this leg on
top okay you see how un flexible I am
see this right
here that and this this is going to open
up this part of your leg and you can
just rest like this and then slowly no
don't push it it'll go down it'll go
down L down right and let do it on the
other
side I think I think that's one of the
most important poses that we tech people
could ever do because that that uh
releases your hips lens up your hips a
lot and uh It prepares you to be able to
do half lootus and polos and stuff like
that um pigeon does the same thing uh so
but I I have put those poses here there
to open up my hips
before I do Banos which is full Lotus
you know with stuff behind your head now
you can do that pose and just put Timber
pose Timber log pose there log pose
instead and then you know the bending
over and then there's then I do this
pose right here this is this is full
Lotus and then this is the one where you
elevate yourself and you you you hold
yourself up which is really fun it's
hard work though this is this is really
really exhausting and then you go down
so that's how I modified the finishing
sequence there there is uh um some other
stuff here that hasn't been shown so um
so let's go back to the primary
series
um uh he has a notice and I'm going to
and the video here this will be enough
for
today um okay so
whoops uhoh where'd it
go so he's he's done he he has a
different take on this and at first I
thought it was really smart and now I
realized how bad it is particularly for
old people
um
so this pose here so these These are
called the balance poses right so these
these come at the beginning after you
finish you know the the the starting
poses you do these um this is these are
sometimes called the standing
poses right because these all happen
before where you go to the ground and I
don't know why he combined these These
are most people who when they divide up
a stonga they divide it up into the
standing poses and then they divide it
into the seated poses and he's mixed
them together so these These are the
balance poses and I I just use a I just
use a a a towel here but as you can see
these are extremely hard to do these are
very hard you have to have flexibility
and you have to have balance and you
these take a tremendous amount of like
strength I don't I can't I can't tell
you how much leg strength the but the
leg strength that they require is the
most important leg strength you can ever
have it's balance strength and one of
the things I noticed is that like I mean
my skating and padding and everything
when I was doing y it just got so good
because my balance got so good and then
over time you lose balance it's one of
the main things you lose especially as
you age and the balance pose is uh I
struggle I struggle with them I have to
to touch the wall sometimes you have to
use there's all things I have to do to
mod but I got to tell you since I've
been doing this regularly for like two
and a half three weeks now when I walk
everything I do is just more based more
grounded more rooted and I can feel that
the muscles in my calves and feet uh and
the nerves have have tuned in to to
being better balanced when I when I I
feel like sort of like a what I imagine
a ballerina ballet dancer would feel
like when they're
rocking uh I'm using a pocket 3 um so so
when we're walking that's that's this
when you're aging these these poses
modifying these poses and making sure
you keep the his Ron Steiner's argument
for getting rid of these is you don't
have the flexibility to do this pose and
you do this exact sequence in the
finishing sequence on the
ground and and I uh do that as well I do
that as well but but I think that doing
the balance pose is so
critical um we're making a video by the
way Mr so so then we
do uh and then I don't do this one I
just hold my foot and do sort of a
variation on tree and then of course we
do we do this one and we do you know
down these are these are the warrior
poses we do that I don't do this fancy
thing that he does it's cool but no um
and then we do the the seated poses all
of them and we go up and J sauce this is
again these are all really great for
cyclist too because they stretch your
hamstrings um and Mar chasa I do that
Mar chasa even though they're considered
Advanced because they they ring out your
organs from all the bad blood they
really do um if you're going to have gas
this is what it's going to
happen because you're that are where the
up dog or the upes and then we do NASA
so half primary ends at
Nasa uh and you do that for that's with
the ab workout okay so the other
modification I don't do anything I don't
do anything in primary past
nasana um these
are they're kind of silly sometimes I'll
throw uh a pigeon whatever this is
called because it's fun but I normally
don't do any of these uh yoga Chita I
mean they're they're kind of silly all
these poses are really kind of silly
honestly um there's just variations on
the other one and lots of yoga studios
will call half primary and they'll just
eliminate all these silly ones but I do
do this one I do that one I do this
one uh but I don't do it um right away
so so let me tell you the variation that
I've done this why the hell would you do
that that is so such a bad idea it is
such a bad idea so what I do is I
skip I skip from NASA which is obviously
great sometimes I used to do 30 sit-ups
after that 30 U be careful you don't do
bad sit-ups that hurt you do you know
cycle sit-ups
I would go from this deasa and I'll go
all the way
to uh back bend and I'll jump past all
this stuff and I'll go straight to back
bend but but in the middle of it and
this is the part I want to really
emphasize
so before I do back bend I do almost 10
minutes of rolling out my back with one
of these and you have to be super
careful and do it very slowly and only
do it in your in your upper back don't
do it in the lower back cuz obviously
you don't need it there and I will I
will rotate it you're going to have to
come watch me do it I'm not going to do
it today I don't have time so I will I
will slide it back a little bit more a
little bit more at pretty much everyone
of my lumber ver vertebrae and you know
the and then I will uh variate vary the
pressure on my back depending and and
God my back pops like crazy when I do
this um and so and what it does is it
opens up your back and so you can
actually vary we can put your arms at
your sides you can put your arms here
you can put your arms way above your
head and you can vary the arch that
happens so you know that you're getting
that sort of you know that reverse Arch
and and and I do that for about 10
minutes every day and I got to tell you
it is one of the I I haven't never done
that before in my practice and it has
totally totally changed my back because
you know you got to be really careful
you got because you know when you're do
it for too long um you can eventually
end up you know overly stressing your
back I mean you got to be very careful
when you come out of it because you put
yourself in a very vulnerable position
by stretching your back in the reverse
way uh so so intensely but I really love
it I I it's that's considered
restorative yoga um and there are
variations on that where people will
just roll up a towel and put across
their back of their shoulders and just
lay there um it's not chakras no
um and um this is not a pose this this
is a this is a PT it's a physical
therapy thing and and so again I'll
start and I'll just rotate it through
the upper back and then I'll go through
the other way and I'll do that for about
10 minutes and then and then I'll just
lay on my back and one of the most
amazing feelings you'll ever have is
just laying on your back after you've
done that because your back is totally
solid on the floor there's no little
spaces that are arched up or anything
and then um to do a reverse pose I'll do
uh after I do that while I'm laying on
my back I will do this this one right
here some variation of this very very
slowly uh just to give a counter pose uh
to the very very intense stretch that
comes from uh rolling your upper back
out and then I'll do uh my w which which
means upside down uh D rasana which is B
pose so um this this pose right here um
it this is a really important pose it's
actually super dangerous if you don't
know what you're doing or you don't have
the strength to do this um back yeah
back good mattress too um but this uh
right here if you can get to the point
where you can David winson's got all the
variations of it but if you can get to
the point where you can do with this
pose I can't tell you how revolutionary
doing back bends has been for me it has
it has given me so much more strength in
my back and if you are a cyclist or if
you are a computer person the thing that
makes you hunch over is that your back
muscles get weak particularly your lower
back muscles and so those muscles can't
keep you you know with good posture and
those muscles get soft and they they
can't do it in particularly and so by
doing this this your your shoulder this
is a good shoulder Builder uh you can do
this upside down you can do this pose
upside down you can grab if if you want
to you can do this pose upside down the
I'm sorry on your stomach you can do it
on your stomach and you can grab your
feet and then just arch your back um
that is a good pose uh that's a good
variation on this but I really really
like this particular pose because it's
it's it really works the shoulders this
really Works your upper shoulder muscles
because you have to hold yourself up the
crap posst doesn't do that um and it it
works your quads uh and it it builds
your the strength in your back and so I
I was not able to do this last time I
tried because I I was too heavy I
couldn't support myself and I was going
to break my ankles if you if you don't
have the strength to support yourself
you end up coming down on your head and
break your neck don't do that it's bad
so you know but I do that you're
supposed to do three of them three to
with a laying down in between uh and and
then of course after you do that they
have a a forward fold I don't do that
because I don't want to do a full chakra
in between so what I do is I come down
after this I'm usually really
exhausted and so I'll lay down and I'll
do the pose where you gra I just grab my
knees and bring them close and I'll roll
out my back I'll roll on my back like a
little kid like a baby like they do and
and then I will do uh I'll go right
after that I jump right into um uh into
the the other poses see she he's doing a
whole transition and and then after that
then I'll do these okay so after that I
know I've moved it but see these poses
are before this pose but I don't do that
I still do these poses but I moved them
I've moved them so I do this pose and
then I come I rest from it because it's
exhausting and then I do a two-legged up
thing kind of like this one because you
need a counter poost for your back while
and I'm already on my back I don't want
to do a full chakr just to be able to
fold over that seems silly to me so
while I'm on my back then I do this then
I do these and these are the same thing
as the balance sequence they're just on
the floor on the ground and it's very
relaxing super duper relaxing it feels
really great um and again it's it's and
then and then after that's
done uh then uh after after that's done
I will go and do um headstand which is
not in this list and after I do H I
already told you the sequence after that
so I'm sorry forearm stand I'll do
forearm stand after that um you know and
I I don't Shakra because I can't do a
true shakras which is also if you do it
wrong it's really bad on your head and
your neck a chakra is basically a
backward sua where your hands are right
here so that when you go but if you do
it right if you do a chakra most people
don't but if you do a back a backward
sumers a backward you know somersault um
most people will like tilt their head
and go around and I sometimes do that
but that's a true chakra SAA is like
straight back and it you can can it
catches your head and at that moment
where it catches your head you're
supposed to push your hands up so that
you can go straight up it's pretty
tricky it's not what people think and I
don't I don't bother with it anything
that's going to mess with my neck I
don't mess with it because my neck is
the vulnerability that I have and I
don't I don't I don't want to pop my
neck I felt I just don't I don't want to
mess with it uh it could be catastrophic
if I pinch a herb up there so um so I
don't I don't do anything there it is
there's a shakr see him see how how bent
over his head is this is why I don't do
chakrasana um and there's really no need
to do it honestly it looks cool that's
it that's really the only reason um and
so yeah so that's that's my sequence
that's uh there's a lot of questions
about that uh this video is actually
intended mostly for people and I will um
probably make a link to this video this
is uh this video is actually intended
mostly for people who' have been
watching me do yoga and have been asking
questions like why are you doing that
sequence what is going on with that
sequence um as I as I the the summation
of it is is that I've altered a stronger
half primary uh to
include uh a little bit more of primary
that include the you the laying down
balance poses uh and I've added I've
taken away shasa and added about 10 to
20 minutes of back rolling which I
consider similar to shasa even though
it's not at the end and I and I do that
right before I do my back bin uh I don't
do any of the folded neck stuff because
I have a weak I have a problem with my
neck and I don't want to mess with it
and that's it so hopefully if you want
to see that in practice please come join
me um if you want to give yoga a try you
can just do the Sun a with me um some of
you may have already noticed I have't
had a couple people comment off CH off
the thing that um that like oh my God
who are you and if you look back at my
other
videos uh lot people only know me from
those videos and they don't know me
before before I started making you know
twitch videos in 2 whatever 19 or
something uh you know back in my yoga
days I you know I had I had more of the
body than I'm getting back right now and
and it will transform you I promise you
I promise you yog yoga will transform
you and I one of the things I really
like about yoga is that unlike CrossFit
or other things which I've done that's
actually how I found out about yoga was
P90X uh Tony Horton who created p9x the
entire CrossFit movement is something
he's like 65 now and he's like a massive
Yogi so he's really really important in
the yoga Community uh for the Western
World and he swears by it calls it the
Fountain of Youth um
one of the reasons that I like it is
because yoga builds the body that I
actually want which is healthy can last
a long time and actually is is bulkier
in places that actually provide Contour
so for example um your your your your
shoulders and your upper chest uh will
get built you'll get big triceps you'll
get you your biceps don't get really
huge um and you don't usually get a huge
back so you get a you get a you get a
strong back you get a strong back and a
strong lower back and but you don't you
don't have that like really wide look
that that body the gym people get and um
but I think the thing I I my wife boy
when my wife does yoga she's just got
she she wears like you know shirtless of
tank tops and you should see the
development that she has in her in her
shoulders and her upper chest it's just
so gorgeous and you know she's got those
little stripy stations in it and stuff
and if you look at if you if you look at
people before and they you can almost
spot a yogi uh it is it's totally good
for old age and bedroom time yeah we
forgot to talk about that yeah so a lot
of those poses we didn't talk about so I
one of them some when I'm doing some of
those Bower forward folds I'm like I'm
like tightening my
mulab uh you're going to have to read
about that I'm not going to tell you
about it it's basically Kel exercises
for men it's actually a part of yoga and
that's one of the reasons uh yogis have
you know it's it's good for prostate
things it's good for sex it's good for
all kinds of stuff
uh in fact I regularly get uh really
turned on after doing yoga because I'm
like you know I'm IND I'm not it's like
I got a hand down there but I'm
massaging my my prostate all the time
every time I do a post because I'm I'm
I'm you know clenching doing kind of a
Kel and I know that's weird to say but
if you don't want to be wearing diapers
in your 70s you better be doing
that if you're not you will be those are
exercises you need to do you need to
keep that that region strong and that's
the only way to do it so um yoga is the
is is really the key to
longevity um and and I think uh
happiness and and it also provides a lot
of dopamine and endorphins uh the reason
I like AO over taiichi uh is because it
does get you heart breathing and pumping
and so I get those wonderful endurance
endorphins that I've come to love you
don't get that from ta Chi I've done ta
Chi before it's really nice it's very
flow it's very meditative but it doesn't
activate dopamine and endorphins the way
that exercise does and AA is more
exercise and taiichi therefore you end
up getting you know a healthy dose of of
yoga high at the end and uh I've come to
be addicted to that feeling uh it's the
reason I like cycling so much so this
has been a really long video in fact
it's probably closer to an hour long
video uh 45 minute video but uh today is
the day off so me talking about yoga
uh is what I'm going to do I'm going to
take the day off uh we take yog we take
moonay off the full moon and half full
moon and no new moon and Saturday and if
you're a woman you take uh your period
days off those are called they call
moonay for women as well so this is why
I'll occasionally be making a takt
talkie video when it once every Saturday
um there's not going to be any Rhyme or
Reason to this these videos but I do um
want to want to talk about it and uh
they will be sort of thematic um I think
next time I've already got other videos
to talk about the eight limbs of banga
but we will be doing you know 30 minute
to to an hour long videos every Saturday
uh regarding yoga uh for old people and
cyclists like me and I'll be talking
about it more from my perspective we
will be covering uh some of the other uh
y one of the things I like to do on my
day off of yoga is to is to practice the
other um uh limbs of a
strunga which are which we'll we'll talk
about but we should we'll probably
actually talk about those next
Saturday uh what if you only have more
LS
LOL on that really bad joke we will end
this video come join me uh every day at
9:00 a.m. except for moondays see you
there